Okay. Good evening, everyone. Today is our lecture two. So, lecture two, we talked about
好的。大家晚上好，今天我们进行了第二讲。那么，在第二讲中，我们讨论了
the number theory. Totally, we have four parts for today's lecture. The part one is about
数论。今天我们讲座分为四个部分，第一部分主要讲述
the divisibility, and from divisibility, we'll talk about the Euclidean algorithm. So, this
这里讨论了可被整除的概念，并由此引出欧几里得算法。因此，我们说，
one is GCD, how we calculate the GCD value. First, we look at the divisibility. This concept
一个是最大公约数，我们是如何计算最大公约数值的。首先，我们要关注可除性的概念
says that we have a long zero b, so b divides a evenly. That means if a can be represented
据说存在一个长零 b，因此 b 能整除 a，这意味着如果 a 可以表示为
as n times b for some n, where a, b, and n are both integers, so one example is just like
对于某些整数 a、b 和 n，a 乘以 n 次 b（n 次），例如，一个例子就是
a 3 divides 6. So, here a is 6, b is 3. So, 6 equals 2 times 3, right? So, n is 2. In
3 能整除 6。因此，这里 a 代表 6，b 代表 3。所以，6 等于 2 乘以 3，对吗？那么，n 的值就是 2。
this equation, we can see there is no remainder on division. So, we can represent this relation
这个方程中，我们可以看到除法没有余数，所以我们可以用这种方式来表示这个关系
to be b divides a, b divides a evenly, and we say that b is a divisor or a factor of a, and a is
若 b 能整除 a，则称 b 是 a 的因数或约数，且 a 能被 b 整除，这种说法更为自然易懂
divisible by b. So, 6 is a factor of 3, a factor of 6. So, 6 is divisible by 3. So, according to
6 可以被 b 整除。所以，6 是 3 的因数，也是 6 的因数。因此，6 能被 3 整除。所以，按照
this definition, we first look at the project dividers of 24. So, the divider of 24, we have
在这个定义中，我们首先来看 24 的项目分隔符。那么，24 的分隔符是...
what? 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 24. So, we have all these dividers of 24. So, the next example
what？1、2、3、4、6、8、12、24 都是 24 的因数。那么，下一个例子
is, minus 5 is a divider of 30, yes or no? Minus 5 divides 60, or 30, yes or no? Yes, right?
减去 5 是 30 的因数吗？减去 5 能整除 60 或 30 吗？当然可以，没错
Because 30 can be represented as minus 5 times minus 6. So, we say yes. 17 is a divider of 0, yes or no?
因为 30 可以表示为负 5 乘以负 6，所以我们说“是”。17 是 0 的因数，对吗？
Yes, right? Because 0 can be represented as 17 times 0. So, this b, this a, b cannot be 0.
是的，没错？因为 0 可以表示为 17 个 0 相乘。因此，这里的 b 和 a 都不能是 0。这样的表达更符合中文的表达习惯。
For division, we have this division algorithm. So, this algorithm says that for any positive
对于除法，我们有一个这样的除法算法。因此，该算法指出，对于任何正数
integer n and any non-negative integer a, if we divide a by n, we can get an integer
整数 n 和任意非负整数 a，用 a 除以 n 后，结果可以是一个整数
quotient q and an integer remainder r. So, a can be represented as q times n plus r,
分数 q 和一个整数余数 r。所以，a 可以表示为 q 乘以 n 再加上 r，表达得更为自然。
q is quotient, and r is a remainder. And r is a remainder, that means r should be
q 是商，r 是余数。而且 r 作为余数，这就意味着 r 应当是
bigger than or equal to 0, but smaller than n. So, we divide a by n, and q is the quotient,
大于等于 0 且小于 n，所以我们将 a 除以 n，q 为商
and this is the flow. Flow of a divides n. So, flow means the largest integer
这是流程描述。它指的是 n 除法中的最大整数
that is smaller than or equal to the given data. For example, 3.3, the flow is 3,
那个值小于或等于给定数据。例如，3.3，则流程数为 3，
the flow of 3 is 3. The largest integer that's smaller than or equal to the given data. So,
3 的流动值为 3，即小于或等于给定数据的最大整数。因此，
q is a quotient. And also, this r remainder, we can represent this one as a mod n, a mod n,
q 是商，而 r 是余数，我们可以将其表示为 a mod n，即 a 除以 n 的余数。
the remainder will be the result. And also, we use this symbol to represent the mod
剩余部分即为结果，而且我们用此符号来表示模运算
operation to get the remainder to be the result.
获取余数作为结果的操作。
So, to support that, we have a equals q times n plus r. So, this data is a, and in this x-axis,
因此，为了支持这一点，我们有 a 等于 q 乘以 n 再加 r。因此，这些数据对应于 a，位于 x 轴上，
you can see we have q times n, and plus this part, this distance to be r. So, one example is,
你可以看到我们有 q 乘以 n，再加上这部分距离，即为 r。举个例子，是这样的。
suppose a is 70, and n is 15. This is n, and this is the quotient to be 4, and 10 will be the
假设 a 为 70，n 为 15。这是 n，这个商应该是 4，那么 10 将是
remainder, r. So, this is the relationship, quite easy. Okay, based on the division,
剩余，R. 所以说，这关系很简单。好的，根据除法，
we look at this Euclidean algorithm, and this one is one of the basic techniques of number theory,
我们来看看这个欧几里得算法，它是数论中的基础技术之一，
and according to this algorithm, we are able to determine the greatest common divider of the two
根据这个算法，我们可以确定这两个数的最大公约数
positive integers. So, first, we look at the order of greatest common divider, GCD value.
正整数。所以，我们首先来看最大公约数（GCD）的排列顺序。
Okay, the greatest common divider of a and b, that's GCD a, b, e, is the largest integer
好吧，a 和 b 的最大公约数，也就是 GCD(a, b, e)，是最大的整数
that divides both a and b. For example, GCD value of 0 and 0 will be what? 0, yeah, by default,
那个能同时整除 a 和 b 的数。比如，0 和 0 的最大公约数是 0，对吧，默认就是这样的。
we set it to be 0. GCD a and 0 will be what? a. So, suppose if a can be negative, so we set to be
我们将其设为 0。a 和 0 的最大公约数会是多少？a。假设 a 可能是负数的话，那么我们就将其设置为
absolute value of a, a is an integer, right? GCD value a and b equals what? Can you imagine what's
a 的绝对值，a 是个整数吧？a 和 b 的最大公约数会是多少呢？你能想象一下吗？
going to be? It's going to be too complicated. So, this equals GCD
即将发生？这会变得相当复杂。因此，这代表最大公约数
e a, right? The share is the same GCD value. Okay. So, how about the last one, GCD a times n,
e a，对吧？这个份额是相同的最大公约数。那么最后一个怎么算，GCD(a)乘以 n，
and a will be what? a. To be more accurate, it is the absolute value of a. So, an equivalent
那么“a”会是什么？a. 更精确地说，它是“a”的绝对值。因此，一个等价
definition is the GCD value of n, b. That means we want to get the max k, and this k divides a,
定义是 n 和 b 的最大公约数，即我们要找到最大的 k，使得 k 可以整除 a，
and this k also divides b. Okay, the maximum number of this k. We look at this example,
并且这个 k 可以整除 b。那么，这个 k 的最大值是多少呢？让我们来看一个例子，
GCD 6 and 18 will be what? What's the value? 6, right? Because 18 is 6 times 3. The maximum
GCD（最大公约数）6 和 18 会是什么？值是多少？6，没错吧？因为 18 是 6 乘以 3。最大公约数是 6。
divisor for these two numbers is 6. And this is GCD value. And based on the GCD value, we define
这两个数的最大公约数是 6。这就是最大公约数（GCD）的值。根据 GCD 值，我们进行定义
that two integers a and b are relatively prime if their GCD value is 1. So, GCD value is 1. We say
如果两个整数 a 和 b 的最大公约数（GCD）为 1，则称它们互质。因此，GCD 值为 1。我们便说
they are relatively prime. This is an important concept. Are 8 and 15 relatively prime? Yes or
他们互质。这是一个关键概念。8 和 15 互质吗？当然。
no? So, we say yes. The reason is because if we leave all positive divisors of 8 and 5,
那么，我们说“是”。因为如果我们保留 8 和 5 的所有正约数，
8 and 15, we can find that the positive divisors of 8, we have 1, 2, 4, 8, and 15, we have 1,
我们可以找到 8 的正因数包括 1、2、4、8，15 的正因数有 1、
3, 5, 15. So, the largest common divisor of 8 and 15 is 1. So, this shows GCD value,
3、5、15。所以，8 和 15 的最大公约数是 1。这显示了 GCD 的值，
8, 15 is 1. So, we say these two data, they are relatively prime. Okay?
8 和 15 是互质数，也就是说这两个数没有公因数。对吧？
So, how to calculate two integers, their GCD value, we have this Euclidean algorithm.
那么，如何计算两个整数的最大公约数？这里有一个欧几里得算法。
And this is a recursive algorithm. So, this one can quickly calculate the result. The GCD value,
这是一种递归算法。因此，它可以迅速计算出结果。最大公约数（GCD）的值，
the procedure is if q is 0, the result is p. And here, we suppose in this example,
如果 q 为 0，则结果为 p。在此例中，我们假设情况是这样的，使翻译更加自然易懂。
in this representation, we suppose that q is bigger than or equal to 0, but smaller than p.
在这种表示法中，我们假定 q 不小于 0，但小于 p。
Okay? So, if q is 0, the result is p. This is easy to understand because GCD,
好的？所以，如果 q 为 0，结果就是 p。这很容易理解，因为最大公约数（GCD），
p0 is p. So, p is the largest common divisor of both p and 0. Otherwise,
p0 等于 p，因此 p 是 p 和 0 的最大公约数。否则，
we calculate it equals GCD q and p percent q. So, p percent q means the remainder R.
我们计算它等于 q 和 p 的最大公约数，p 除以 q 的余数即为 R。
Because we can represent p to be q times n plus R. So, this GCD,
因为我们可以把 p 表示成 qn 加 R 的形式。因此，这个最大公约数，
pq equals here means GCD q and R. Right? The reason is because, well, the GCD value means
pq 等于这里表示 GCD（最大公约数）q 和 R。对吧？原因在于，嗯，GCD 值代表
the divisor of both p and q. So, p can be represented as, suppose p equals s times
p 和 q 的公因数。所以，p 可以表示为，假设 p 等于 s 的倍数
the GCD value. Okay? No problem, right? GCD is the divisor of p. So, we represent p to be
GCD 值。没问题吧？GCD 是 p 的约数。因此，我们表示 p 为
s times GCD value. And q is also the model of this GCD. So, q can be represented as,
s 代表 GCD 的值。q 是这个 GCD 的模型，所以 q 可以表示为，
let's say, t times GCD value times n. And R, we have the remainder to be R.
假设，t 次最大公约数乘以 n。余数则为 R。
And then this R equals s minus t times n times GCD value. Okay? R equals this one.
然后这个 R 等于 s 减去 t 乘以 n 乘以最大公约数。好的吗？R 就是这个数。
In other words, the GCD value is also a divisor of R.
换句话说，GCD 值同样是 R 的约数。
That true? Okay. So, in other words, we want to calculate the GCD value of both p and q.
那是真的吗？好吧。换句话说，我们想要计算 p 和 q 的最大公约数值。
So, GCD value is a factor of p, is a factor of q. And also, we find that GCD is also a factor of
因此，最大公约数是 p 的因子，也是 q 的因子。此外，我们还发现最大公约数同样是...
R from this equation. Right? GCD is also a factor of R. And this implies, well, if we want to calculate
这个方程中的 R。对吧？GCD 也是 R 的因数。这也意味着，嗯，如果我们想要计算
GCD p, q, then this value can be calculated by the GCD of q and R. So, GCD must be the factor of
计算 p 和 q 的最大公约数后，这个值可以通过计算 q 和 R 的最大公约数来得到。所以，最大公约数必须是
q and R simultaneously. So, because q and R are the values to be much smaller than q. Okay? So,
q 和 R 同时存在，所以 q 和 R 的值要比 q 小得多。好的吗？
in this way, and finally, we recursively call this function. Otherwise, if q is not 0, we get
以此方式，最终我们递归调用这个函数。如果不是 0，则得到
this q and R. And both q and R will be much smaller than t and q. We recursively call this function.
这里 q 和 R。q 和 R 都远小于 t 和 q。我们递归调用这个函数，表达更自然。
And finally, the R position can be 0. And we have t to be the output.
最后，R 的位置可以是 0，我们要求 t 作为输出。
So, here is a flow to apply the Euclidean algorithm. So, suppose here we start, we want to get
因此，这里有一个应用欧几里得算法的流程。假设我们从这个点开始，我们的目标是得到
the GCD a and b. And suppose a to be bigger than b. If yes, we divide a by b and put in the remainder.
求 a 和 b 的最大公约数。若 a 大于 b，则将 a 除以 b，并记录下余数。
So, this means a can be represented as a equals b times n plus R. And we look at R. If R is bigger
因此，这意味着 a 可以表示为 a 等于 b 乘以 n 加上余数 R。我们来看看 R。如果 R 的值更大
than 0, we replace a with b. So, this GCD a, b equals GCD b and R. Until R equals 0,
如果大于 0，则用 b 替换 a。所以，a 和 b 的最大公约数等于 b 和 R 的最大公约数。直到 R 等于 0，
then the result, the GCD a, b, or we say it is b, R equals, if R is 0, the result is b at this moment.
那么结果就是 GCD(a, b)，或者说它是 b，如果 R 为 0，那么此刻的结果就是 b。
Now, we look at this example. Suppose we want to get the GCD value
现在，让我们来看这个例子。假设我们要计算最大公约数（GCD）的值
7, 10, and 3, 10. Yeah, here. We want to calculate this value. So, this one, well, this is p,
7、10 和 3、10，对吧。这里我们要计算这个数值。那么，这个，嗯，这个就是 p，
t is 7, 10, q is 3, 10, and this is R. According to the Euclidean algorithm, this one equals
t 等于 7，10，q 等于 3，10，这是 R。根据欧几里得算法，它等于
the GCD value, q is 3, 10, R is 90, q and R. And here we continue this process. So, this is q,
最大公约数，q 为 3、10，R 为 90，q 和 R。然后我们继续这个过程。所以这是 q，翻译得更加自然和易懂。
this is R, and this is R1. So, this equals the GCD value, q is 90. Now, we have equals
这是 R，这是 R1。因此，等于最大公约数，q 值为 90。现在，我们得到等于
this p, this is q, so this is q, this R equals R, R is 90, and R1, 40. So, this is
这 p，这是 q，因此也是 q，R 等于 R，R 的值为 90，R1 为 40。因此这是
R, this is R1. So, every step you can see the p, r becomes smaller compared to the previous
R，这是 R1。因此，每一步你都能观察到 p 和 r 的值相较于上一步有所减小
p, q, and we continue this process. This is R, this is R1, we have R2, so this equals GCD,
p, q，然后我们继续这个过程。这是 R，这是 R1，我们有 R2，因此这代表最大公约数，
R1, R2, 40, and R2 is 10. And we continue this process. So, we have R1 and R2 plus 0. 0 is R3,
R1、R2、40，其中 R2 为 10。我们持续这个过程。因此，我们得到 R1 和 R2 加 0，0 即为 R3，
right? And this equals GCD, R2, and R3. So, R2 is 10, R3 is 0. So, because the R value is 0,
right？这等于最大公约数、R2 和 R3。因此，R2 为 10，R3 为 0。由于 R 值为 0，
and the output is this 10. So, after 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 5 steps, we get the result to be 10.
因此输出结果是 10。经过 1、2、3、4、5、5 步后，我们得到了 10 这个结果。
And this is a positive to calculate the GCD value by applying the Euclidean algorithm.
这段内容是关于通过应用欧几里得算法计算最大公约数值的正例。翻译经过润色，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
Another example is suppose we have this a, b, a, b, both n, b are very large. And well, even no
另一个例子，假设我们有这样的 a, b, a, b，其中 n 和 b 都很大。嗯，甚至没有...
matter how large it is, we can quickly get the result after a number of steps. So, this is a,
无论大小，我们都能在几个步骤后迅速得到结果。因此，这……
b, this is q, and R1. And GCD a, b equals GCD. So, here is a equals b times q1 plus R1. So, this
b, 这是 q，还有 R1。GCD(a, b)等于 GCD。因此，这里 a 等于 b 乘以 q1 加上 R1。所以，
equals b, R1. So, b, R1. And we recursively call the calculation. So, this equals GCD,
等于 b 和 R1，因此我们递归地进行计算。所以这等于最大公约数，
R1, R2. So, R1 is here, R2 is a remainder. So, we continue to process until we have.
R1, R2。所以，R1 在这里，R2 是余数。我们继续处理，直到处理完毕。
So, it equals GCD in this row, R7, and R8. And equals GCD, R8, R9. So, R8 is this one, R9.
因此，它等于这一行的最大公约数，即 R7 和 R8。也等于 R8 和 R9 的最大公约数。所以，R8 就是指这个，R9。
Is this one. And continually, we have equals GCD, R9, R10.
这就是。而且，我们持续有等于 GCD、R9、R10。
R sub 10, okay? This one. Because R sub 10 is 0, so, this one equals R9. And this is an output.
R10，好的？这个。因为 R10 等于 0，所以这个就等于 R9。这是输出。
To be the value of this, it needs to be 10b.
要成为这个值的数值，它必须是 10b。
So, everything looks fine, right? At this moment. If, well, everything is fine,
那么，目前一切看起来都很顺利，对吧？现在是这样的。如果一切正常的话，
can you do the calculation of this exercise one? I'll give you three minutes. You tell me what's
你能帮我计算这个练习题吗？我给你三分钟，然后告诉我结果。
the result. The GCD is 93 and 16.
结果为。93 和 16 的最大公约数是。
What's the result for this? One. Okay. So, we can repeat. We can use the Euclidean
这个结果是什么？一个。好的，所以我们可以重复使用欧几里得距离
algorithm to calculate. So, this 93 can be represented as 16 times 5 plus 13.
算法计算的内容。所以，这个 93 可以表示为 16 乘以 5 加上 13。
And 13, 16. So, next one, we look at 16 and 13. 16. 16 equals 13 times 1 plus 3. And we look at
所以，接下来我们看看 16 和 13。16 等于 13 乘以 1 再加 3。然后我们继续看
13 and 3. 13 equals 3 times 4 plus 1, right? And we have 3 and 1. So, 3 equals 1 times 3 plus 0.
13 和 3。13 等于 3 乘以 4 再加 1，对吧？然后我们有 3 和 1。所以，3 等于 1 乘以 3 再加 0。
So, these three, this one is GCD 31. So, finally, this one equals GCD 31 and 10.
那么，这三个数中，这个数的最大公约数是 31。最终，这个数等于 31 和 10 的最大公约数。
So, this one. So, this corresponds to this row. This corresponds to this row. Equals 10.
那么，这个。这对应表格中的这一行。这对应表格中的这一行。等于 10。
Okay. This is a very easy part. Part one, just an appetizer. Okay?
好的。这部分很简单。第一部分，仅仅是个开胃小菜。好吗？
Now, we go to part two. Based on our understanding of the Euclidean algorithm,
现在，我们进入第二部分。根据我们对欧几里得算法的理解，
how to calculate the GCD value. So, now we need to move to part two about the modular arithmetic.
如何计算最大公约数（GCD）值。所以，现在我们要进入第二部分，讲解模运算。
And then we need to learn the expanded Euclidean algorithm to get the modular inverse.
然后我们需要学习扩展欧几里得算法，以便获取模逆元。这样的表述更自然、易懂。
So, modular inverse is an important concept in the cryptography.
因此，模逆是密码学中的一个重要概念，是一个关键概念。
Okay. First, we look at the modular arithmetic. The modulus was a modulus in this modular operation.
好的。首先，让我们来探讨一下模运算。在这个模运算中，“模”指的是模数。
Suppose we have A to be an integer and N is a positive integer. We can define A mod N to be
假设 A 是一个整数，N 为正整数。我们可以定义 A 除以 N 的余数为
the remainder value where A is divided by N. And this integer N is called the modulus.
A 除以 N 的余数，整数 N 被称为模数。
Suppose for given integer A, A can be represented as Q times M plus R. We note that
假设对于给定的整数 A，它可以表示为 Q 乘以 M 再加上 R。我们注意到
Q is quotient, right? And R is the remainder. Then A can be represented as this is the Q
Q 代表商，R 代表余数。因此，A 可以表示为这是 Q
value times N plus this is R value. R value can be represented as A mod N. A mod N. A divided by N,
值乘以 N 再加上这个 R 值。R 值可以表示为 A 除以 N 的余数。A 除以 N 的余数。A 除以 N，
we want to know what the remainder value. So, for example, 11 mod 7 was our result.
我们想知道余数是多少。比如，11 除以 7 的余数就是我们的结果。
4, right? 11 equals 7 plus 4. So, 4 is a remainder. How about minus 11 mod 7? What do we want?
4，对吧？11 等于 7 加 4，所以 4 是余数。那么，-11 除以 7 的余数是多少呢？我们想要知道什么？
So, minus 11 can be represented as 7 times minus 2 plus 3, right? Plus 3. So, normally,
那么，减去 11 可以表示为 7 个负 2 加 3，对吧？再加 3。所以，一般来说，
we want to have our long negative value to be the remainder. So, this one is 3.
我们希望将长负数作为余数，因此这个值为 3。
For the mod operation, we have this concept, congruent mod N. Two integers A and B are said
对于模运算，有一个概念叫做同余模 N。两个整数 A 和 B，我们称它们为
to be congruent mod N if A mod N equals B mod N. This is written as A is congruent to B mod N.
如果 A 除以 N 的余数等于 B 除以 N 的余数，则称 A 与 B 对 N 同余。这可以写作 A ≡ B (mod N)。
So, both of them divided by N have the same remainder.
因此，它们两个除以 N 的余数是一样的。
For example, 73. So, 73 can be represented as
例如，73，所以它可以被表示为
23 times 3 plus 4. And that 73 is congruent to 4 mod 23, right? So, 4 divided by 23,
23 乘以 3 再加 4，那么 73 和 4 对 23 取模同余，对吧？所以 4 除以 23，
the remainder is 4. And 73 divided by 23, the remainder is 4. So, they're the same. We say
剩余数都是 4。73 除以 23 的余数同样是 4，因此它们是相同的。我们可以说
they are congruent when we have mod 23 in this operation. And 21 is congruent to 1 when mod N.
当我们进行模 23 运算时，它们是同余的。在模 N 的情况下，21 与 1 同余。
Okay. Now, if A is congruent to 0 mod N, that means N is a factor of A.
好的。现在，如果 A 与 0 模 N 同余，那么 N 就是 A 的因数。
N is a factor of A. First, A divided by N, the remainder will be 0. The remainder will be 0.
N 是 A 的因数。首先，A 除以 N，余数为 0，余数确实为 0。
Okay. We look at this one. Actually, this is a very important zero. So, this one says that
好的。我们来看看这个。实际上，这个零非常重要。所以，它说的是
if GCD value of U and Z is 1. So, U and Z is 1, means these two are relative prime.
如果 U 和 Z 的最大公约数为 1，那么这两个数就是互质的，即它们之间没有其他公约数。
So, these two numbers are relative prime. Then U times X is coming to U times Y mod Z
因此，这两个数互质。那么，U 乘以 X 等于 U 乘以 Y 对 Z 取模
UZ are relative prime. This U can be cancelled. And we have X is congruent to Y mod Z.
UZ 互质。U 可以约掉。因此，X 与 Y 模 Z 同余。
So, this is a good problem. So, one example is 3 times 3 is 9 is congruent to 3 times 11.
因此，这是一个好问题。举个例子，3 乘以 3 等于 9，和 3 乘以 11 同余。
This is congruent to 1 when we take the mod 8. Because 3 and 8 are relative prime,
这在取模 8 时与 1 同余，因为 3 和 8 互质，所以...
so this implies this 3 can be cancelled. This implies 3 is congruent to 11 when we take mod 8.
这意味着 3 可以被约去。这意味着当我们对 8 取模时，3 和 11 是同余的。这样的表达更符合中文习惯。
However, although we have 3 times 4 is congruent to 5 times 4 is congruent to 4
然而，尽管 3 乘 4 等于 5 乘 4，也等于 4 乘 4，它们同余
when we have the mod 8 operation. Well, we cannot cancel this form.
当我们进行模 8 运算时。嗯，这个形式无法被取消。
So, the reason is because 4 and 8 are not relative prime. If we move 4 from both sides,
因此，原因在于 4 和 8 不是互质数。如果我们把 4 从等式两边移除，
left hand side and right hand side, can we get 3 is congruent to 5 mod 8? Of course not, right?
左边和右边，3 和 5 模 8 同余吗？当然不行，对吧？
So, the reason is because the common factor 4 is not relative prime to 8. So, it cannot be cancelled.
因此，原因是公因数 4 和 8 不互质，所以不能约分。
Only if the common divisor number 3 is relative prime to the mod 8, then 3 can be cancelled.
只有当 3 与 8 的模数互质时，3 才能被约去。
This is a good problem.
这是一个很好的问题。
Some other good problem is if we want to calculate a plus b mod n, we can first
如果我们要计算 a 加 b 模 n 的值，可以先
calculate a mod n and then plus b mod n. This will make the result to be much smaller and to have
计算模 n 的结果，然后再加上 b 模 n。这样可以使结果变得非常小，并且具有
an easier calculation and similar for the minus operation and the multiplication operation.
一个更简单的计算，以及类似减法和乘法操作的情况。
So, one example is suppose we want to calculate 2 1 1 mod 8.
因此，这里有一个例子：假设我们要计算 2 的 1 次方的 1 次方对 8 取模。
So, 2 1 1 mod 8 should be 3, 1 to 5 mod 8 will be 5. So, these two, the sum
因此，2 除以 8 余 3，1 到 5 除以 8 余 5。所以这两个数的和是
the sum mod 8 equals the mod result 3 plus 5 mod 8 and this should be 0.
8 取余的结果等于 3 加 5 的 8 取余，结果应当为 0。
For the minus also, we can have this equation to quickly get the result. So, 2 1 1 is 3,
对于减法来说，我们也可以用这个公式快速计算出结果。因此，2 减 1 等于 3。
minus 5, this mod 8, the result is what? The result is 6. Minus 2, we have 1, it should be 6.
减去 5，对 8 取模的结果是 6。减去 2 后，我们得到 1，但应该是 6。
And this multiplication equals 3 times 5, mod 8, the result is what? 7.
这道乘法等于 3 乘以 5，对 8 取模，结果是 7。
Okay, we look at this table. This table suppose this row represents
好的，我们来看看这张表格。这张表格假设这一行所表示的内容
so this row we have a and this column we have b and we have in the table which shows
这一行是 a，那一列是 b，表格中展示了
the result a plus b mod 8.
a+b 对 8 取模的结果
0 plus 0, the result mod 8 is 0. And also we can find in this diagonal line,
0 加 0 等于 0，对 8 取模的结果也是 0。此外，您还可以在这条对角线上找到这一点，
the result is 0. So, 1 plus 7 is 8, mod 8 is 0. So, everyone we can find a corresponding value here
结果为 0，因此 1 加 7 等于 8，对 8 取模后结果为 0。因此，我们可以在这一部分找到一个相应的值
such that the sum mod 8 is 0. This is the addition operation.
这样求和模 8 等于 0，这是加法操作。翻译得更加自然易懂。
Well, here we show the result to be a times b mod 8 result. So, this is a, this is b plus for
嗯，这里我们展示了 a 乘以 b 再对 8 取模的结果。因此，这是 a，这是 b 加 4
number 1 times 1, mod 8 is 1. However, for 2 times something, if b is 2, the whole row
数字 1 乘以 1，模 8 等于 1。但是，对于 2 乘以某个数（例如 b=2）的情况，整行
we cannot find any number to be 1. So, in the multiplication, we look at the result, the product
我们找不到任何数等于 1。因此，在乘法运算中，我们关注的是乘积的结果
mod 8 to be 1. So, in the row for b plus 2 cannot find anyone, if b equals 3, we find a value such
模 8 等于 1，因此当 b 加 2 的行中找不到对应值时，若 b 等于 3，则找到一个对应的值
that a equals 3, there mod 8 result is 1. So, the sum there can be 1 plus not all the a or b value
那个 a 等于 3，对 8 取模的结果是 1。因此，那个数列的和可以是 1 加上 a 或 b 的非全部值
we can find ourselves for the product value mod 8 to be 1.
我们可以找到使产品值对 8 取模等于 1 的情况，表达更为自然。
So, then we define the additive and the multiplicative inverse mod 8.
因此，我们先定义了模 8 的加法和乘法逆元。这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
So, this is the definition of the inverse value mod given number 8. So, we define that the additive
因此，这是关于给定数字 8 的逆模值的定义。我们将其定义为加法
inverse is your w plus minus w is coming to 0 mod 8. And this minus w is called the additive
逆元是您的 w 加减 w 等于 0 模 8。这个减去 w 的数，我们称之为加法逆元
inverse, additive inverse, because we have this addition, right, we add them together. This is
因为存在加法运算，所以我们有相反数和加法逆元，对吧，将它们相加。这就是
for the additive inverse of w mod 8. Well, if w is 0, so minus w will be 0. So, here is
对于 w 模 8 的加法逆元。如果 w 为 0，那么它的相反数也是 0。因此，这里就是
additive inverse, 0 plus 0, mod 8 is 0. If w is 1, the additive inverse will be 7, 1 plus 7, mod 8
加法逆元，0 加 0 等于 0（模 8）。若 w 为 1，则其加法逆元为 7，即 1 加 7（模 8）
is 0. For every w, we have corresponding minus w to be the additive inverse of w mod 8. We have
对于每个 w，都存在对应的-w，它是 w 模 8 的加法逆元。具体来说，我们有
all the values here. However, for multiplicative inverse, so multiplicative inverse defines as
所有这些值。然而，所谓的乘法逆元是指
w times the w to minus 1. And the result is coming to 1 when we have the mod 8
w 乘以 w 减 1，对 8 取模后结果为 1
operation. This is the definition to be the multiplicative inverse of w. We denote this value
这是 w 的乘法逆元的定义。我们记这个值为
to be w to minus 1. If w is 1, this modular inverse should be 1. 1 times 1, here is multiplication.
如果 w 等于 1，那么这个模逆元应该是 1。1 乘以 1，这里就是乘法操作。
1 times 1 is 1, so mod 8 is 1. However, for 2, 4, 6, we do not have the modular inverse,
1 乘以 1 等于 1，所以对 8 取模结果为 1。但是，对于 2、4、6 这三个数，我们找不到它们的模逆元，
the multiplicative inverse mod 8. For 3, w equals 3, the w to minus 1 is 3. 3 times 3 is 9.
8 的乘法逆元。对于数字 3，其逆元是 3，即 3 减 1 等于 3。3 乘以 3 等于 9。
This is congruent to 1. We have mod 8 operation. Check here.
这是等于 1 的，我们进行了模 8 运算，请在此处查看。
For some w, we have the multiplicative inverse. This w to the minus 1 is called the multiplicative
对于某些 w，存在其乘法逆元。w 的-1 次幂被称为乘法逆元。
inverse. Some properties for this modular operation are, for example, for this Zn,
逆运算。例如，对于这个 Zn，该模块化操作的一些属性，比如包括，
so Zn is set with all integers from 0, 1 to a mass 1. We have 40 properties. The first one is
因此，Zn 被设置为从 0 到 1 以及质量为 1 的所有整数。我们共有 40 个属性。第一个属性是
commutative loss. That means for addition and multiplication, we can swap the first and second
交换律损失，即对于加法和乘法运算，我们可以互换第一个和第二个操作数
data to the result of the same. For solutive loss means, well, for this addition or multiplication,
数据从输入到输出结果。对于求解损失而言，嗯，对于这种加法或乘法操作，
we can first calculate the first two or the second two to the result of the same.
我们可以先计算前两个数或后两个数，结果是一样的。
Then, distributive law means the w can be in this parenthesis, w times x plus y equals w times x
然后，根据分配律，w 可以放在这个括号中，w 乘以 x 加 y 等于 w 乘以 x
plus w times y. Identity means some data plus the w itself or times w itself equals itself.
加上 w 乘以 y。身份意味着某些数据加上 w 本身，或者乘以 w 本身等于自身。这样的表述更符合中文的表达习惯。
So this identity in addition is 0. In multiplication is 1.
因此这个身份加起来为 0，相乘为 1。
In two different scenarios, the identity value will be different.
在两种不同的情况下，身份值会有所不同。
A detailed inverse will be minus w. That means for each w in this set, there exists a z such that
详细的逆映射意味着减去 w，也就是说，对于这个集合中的每一个 w，都存在一个 z，使得
w plus z is 0 mod m. So this z, we always can find this z. So this z, we call it to be
w 加 z 对 m 取模等于 0。因此，这个 z 我们总能找到，我们将其称为
a detailed inverse, to be mass w.
一个详细的逆向方案，适用于大规模生产
For example, if w is 1, then z is a mass 1. If w is 2, then z is a mass 2.
例如，若 w 值为 1，则 z 代表质量 1；若 w 值为 2，则 z 代表质量 2。
We can always find this z to be a detailed inverse for a given w.
我们总能找到这样一个 z，它是给定 w 的一个详细的逆元。
Will we care about the modular inverse for the multiplication? This is our equation.
我们会关心乘法的模逆吗？这可是我们的方程式哦。
Now, we said that x is a modular inverse of a mod d if a times x mod d equals 1.
现在，我们说，如果 a 乘以 x 模 d 等于 1，那么 x 就是 a 模 d 的模逆。这样的表述更加自然易懂。
Here is a definition of a modular inverse for the multiplication.
这里是对乘法中模逆的定义（经过润色）。
x is denoted as a to the mass 1 mod b. So between a times x mod b equals 1, x is denoted to be
x 表示为 a 对 b 取模 1，即 a 乘以 x 对 b 取模等于 1 时，x 表示为
the multiplicative inverse of a mod b. So x is a modular inverse.
a 模 b 的乘法逆元，即 x 是模逆元。
So we have examples here. Because 3 times 5 is equal to 1 mod 7. 3 times 5 is 15.
这里有一些例子。因为 3 乘以 5 在模 7 的情况下余 1。3 乘以 5 等于 15。
So we say 3 is a modular inverse of 5 mod 7.
我们说 3 是 5 除以 7 的余数为 1，因此它是 5 模 7 的模逆元。
In other words, because this definition is 5 to the mass 1 times 5 mod 7 is 1.
换句话说，因为这个定义是 5 的 1 次方乘以 5 再对 7 取模等于 1。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
So this 5 mod 1 modular inverse of 5 equals what?
这 5 除以 1 的模逆数是多少？5 等于多少？
Equals what?
等于什么？
This is a mass 1 to the mass 1 mod 7 equals what?
这是质量 1 除以 7 的余数是多少？
So which number is a modular inverse of 5?
那么哪个数是 5 的模逆数？
Which number?
哪个数字？
The definition is 5, modular inverse of 5 is 5 mass 1 times 5 mod 7 should be 1.
定义是 5，5 的模逆数是 5，5 乘以 1 再模 7 的结果应该是 1。
And we have 3 times 5 mod 7 is 1. So this modular inverse of 5 equals 3.
我们知道 3 乘以 5 模 7 的结果是 1，因此 5 的模逆元就是 3。
And similarly, because 7 times 7 is equal to 1 mod 16. So this 7 represents modular inverse of 7.
同样地，因为 7 乘以 7 等于 1 模 16。因此，这个 7 表示 7 的模逆元。
So this 7 to the mass 1 mod 16 is 7.
因此，1 对 16 取模后，7 除以这个结果等于 7。
However, there is no modular inverse for 8 mod 14. So that means we don't have this 8 mass 1,
然而，8 除以 14 没有模逆元，所以这意味着我们无法表示 8 的质量为 1，
this value such that 8 mass 1 times 8 is equal to 1 mod 14.
这个值满足 8 乘以 1 等于 1 模 14（使翻译更自然易懂）。
No such modular inverse.
没有这样的模逆（更自然和易懂的翻译）
No such data such that the demand times 8 mod 14 equals 1.
没有这样的数据，使得需求量乘以 8 后对 14 取模的结果为 1。
In fact, we have this theorem. There exists a modular inverse for A mod B
事实上，我们有一个定理：对于 A 模 B，确实存在一个逆元。
even though only if A is relative prime to B.
即使只有当 A 与 B 互质时，才满足条件。
So that means we have this A to the mass 1 modular inverse of A. So A times A mass 1 is
这意味着我们得到了 A 关于质量 1 的模逆，即 A 乘以 A 质量 1 等于
congruent to 1 mod B. And this implies GCD AB must be 1. So in this example, because the GCD
So in this example, because the GCD 814 is what?
在这个例子中，GCD 814 是什么？
The greatest common divisor of 8 and 14 is what? 8 and 14 is what?
8 和 14 的最大公约数是多少？8 和 14 指的是什么？
2, right? It is not 1. The not relative prime. So we don't have the 8 to the mass 1.
2，对吧？它不是 1。它和 1 不互质。因此，我们无法用 8 乘以 1。
Not 1.
不是 1（更自然的翻译）
So that means we don't have the modular inverse for 8 mod 14.
这就是说，我们还没有找到 8 除以 14 的模逆元。
Well, the modular inverse is critical. The reason is because in the RSA algorithm,
好吧，模逆是至关重要的。这是因为 RSA 算法中，
we have public key, we have private key, E and D, right? So E is the public key
我们有公钥和私钥，还有 E 和 D，对吧？所以 E 是公钥
and D is the private key.
并且 D 是私钥。
To get public key, we require that E times D is congruent to 1 mod some value. And this value is 5m.
获取公钥时，我们需要 E 乘以 D 与某个值同余 1。这个值是 5m。为了使表达更自然易懂，可以改为：“获取公钥需要满足 E 乘以 D 与某个值同余 1 的条件，这个值是 5m。”
You see? E times D. So E is the modular inverse of E mod 5m. This public key and private key,
你看？E 乘以 D，所以 E 是 5m 模下的模逆元。这个公钥和私钥，
that relationship is a modular inverse relationship.
那种关系是模逆关系。
In this public key scheme, in this RSA algorithm, that's the reason we need to
在这个公钥方案和 RSA 算法中，这正是我们之所以需要这样做的原因
amplify the modular inverse scheme.
放大模逆方案（优化版）。
So in RSA algorithm, we need to decide the public key, even the public key.
在 RSA 算法中，我们需要确定公钥，甚至包括公钥。
The relationship should satisfy E times D with congruent to 1 mod 5m.
该关系应满足 E 乘以 D，与 1 模 5m 同余。
Okay, so now we want to have a formal way to calculate the modular inverse of A mod n
好的，现在我们想要有一种正式的方式来计算 A 对 n 取模的模逆
according to the calculation. To do the calculation, we can resort to this phase of identity.
根据计算结果。为了进行计算，我们可以借助这个身份阶段。
So phase of identity states that for any given integer A and B,
因此，身份状态阶段指出，对于任何给定的整数 A 和 B，…
we can find such integer x and y such that A times x plus
我们可以找到这样的整数 x 和 y，使得 A 乘以 x 加上
A times x plus B times y equals their GCD value, GCD AB. So this is a phase of identity
A 乘以 x 加上 B 乘以 y 等于它们的最大公约数，即 GCD(AB)。因此，这是身份阶段
for any given integers and B. There exist x and y, integers x and y to satisfy this equation.
对于任意整数和 B，总存在整数 x 和 y，它们满足该方程。
Okay, so this phase of identity tells you that if N, B are relative to 1,
好吧，所以这个身份阶段告诉你，如果 N 和 B 是相对于 1 而言的，
or relative to 1, so if
相对于 1，因此如果
GCD A and B equals 1, so AB relatively to 1,
A 和 B 的最大公约数为 1，因此 AB 相对于 1，
then we are able to calculate the A's modular inverse mod B.
我们可以计算出 A 对 B 的模逆
So what does it mean? If GCD AB equals 1, we can find such A x plus B y equals 1.
那这个是什么意思呢？如果 AB 的最大公约数是 1，我们就能找到这样的 A 乘以 x 加上 B 乘以 y 等于 1。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
Well, at both sides, we have mod, for example, mod B. If A x plus B y mod B,
好吧，在两边我们都有模运算，比如模 B。如果 A 乘以 B 加上 B 乘以 y 再对 B 取模，
this equals 1 mod B. For such, we take the mod operation. So this implies your B times 1,
这等于 1 对 B 取模。因此，我们进行取模运算。这意味着 B 乘以 1，
this multiple B, this part is 0. Okay, so that means, well, the left-hand side equals A x mod B
这是多个 B，这部分代表 0。所以，左边等于 A x mod B
is 1. So this implies A x is relative to 1 mod B. So this x is what? x is the modular inverse of A.
因此，这意味着 A x 相对于 1 模 B。那么这个 x 是什么？它是 A 的模逆元。这样的表述更符合中文的表达习惯。
So this x equals A to the mod 1 mod B.
因此，这个 x 等于 A 除以 B 的余数。
x is the modular inverse of A mod B in this case. According to this phase of identity,
在这个例子中，x 是 A 模 B 的模逆。根据这一身份阶段，
if A and B are with fun, then we can find this x and y. So x, we call it to be the modular inverse of A mod D.
如果 A 和 B 在一起玩得开心，那么我们就能找到这个 x 和 y。因此，我们将 x 称为 A 模 D 的模逆。
We find the modular inverse of A successfully in this case.
我们成功找到了 A 的模逆元，表述更为自然。
And similarly, if at both sides with mod A, so this implies A x plus B y,
如果在两边都除以模 A，这就意味着 A 乘以 x 加上 B 乘以 y，表达得更为自然
we take the mod A operation. So this equals 1 mod A, and this A times x mod A is 0.
我们进行模 A 运算。所以，这等于 1 除以 A 的余数，而 A 乘以 x 除以 A 的余数是 0。
So B y mod A equals 1. In other words, B y is coming to 1 mod A. So this y represents
因此，B y 模 A 等于 1，换句话说，B y 等于 1 模 A。这个 y 表示
modular inverse of B when it has a mod A operation.
B 在模 A 运算下的模逆元（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So here, this is an implication of the modular inverse for this parameter A x and B y.
因此，这里就是参数 A x 和 B y 的模逆的推论。这使得表达更加自然易懂。
So this is an implication for this phase of identity in this equation.
因此，这是对这个方程中这一阶段身份的一个推论。这个推论更加自然和易于理解。
Because the result is gcd value, how to calculate gcd value? We can use the Euclidean algorithm.
因为结果是最大公约数，那么如何计算最大公约数呢？我们可以使用欧几里得算法。这样的表述更加自然易懂。
Euclidean algorithm can help you to calculate the gcd value. And we can use extended Euclidean
欧几里得算法能帮助您计算最大公约数值。此外，我们还可以使用扩展欧几里得算法
algorithm to solve the initial equation to find x1. Once you find x, you find the modular inverse
算法用于求解初始方程以找到 x1。找到 x 之后，再求其模逆，使翻译更加自然易懂
of A. So x is here, y is here. But we can use the extended Euclidean algorithm to find the modular
在这里，x 位于此处，y 位于此处。然而，我们可以利用扩展欧几里得算法来求解模
inverse of A, that's x. Modular inverse of B, that's y. Now let's look at how we can
A 的逆元是 x，B 的逆元是 y。现在我们来探讨一下
use the extended Euclidean algorithm to find the modular inverse of 911 mod 999.
使用扩展欧几里得算法求解 911 模 999 的模逆数
So we won't find the modular inverse of 911 mod 999 according to the Bezos identity. If this one is A,
因此，根据贝佐斯公式，我们无法找到 911 除以 999 的模逆元。如果这个数是 A，
this one is B. So we have A x plus B y equals gcd A B. Is that right?
这一个是 B，所以 A 乘以 x 加上 B 乘以 y 等于 A 和 B 的最大公约数，这个说法正确。
A is 911, B is 999. First we need to guarantee that this gcd
A 是 911，B 是 999。首先，我们必须保证这个 gcd
911 999, it is 0, or it is 1. If it is 1, we can find some x. So x will be modular inverse of A
911 999，要么是 0，要么是 1。如果是 1，我们就能找到一些 x。这时，x 就是 A 的模逆元
mod B according to the Bezos identity.
根据贝索斯身份的模块 B（经过润色）。
So here you can see we satisfied this equation. We say x is a modular inverse of A mod B.
这里您可以看到我们成功解决了这个方程。我们称 x 为 A 模 B 的模逆元。
That's exactly. x is a modular inverse of A mod B. A is here, B is here. If their gcd value is 1.
那正是。x 是 A 模 B 的模逆元。A 在这里，B 在这里。如果它们的最大公约数为 1。
So now we look at how we can calculate this modular inverse.
现在我们来探讨如何计算这个模逆，使翻译更加自然易懂。
So the first step is we still need to guarantee that the gcd A B is 1. We apply the Euclidean
因此，第一步是确保 A 和 B 的最大公约数为 1。我们采用欧几里得算法。
algorithm to guarantee that this is true. So from the Euclidean algorithm, this is A, this is B,
算法确保这一点是真的。因此，根据欧几里得算法，这是 A，这是 B，
this is R, this is B, this is R, this is R1, this is R, this is R1, R2, so on and so forth.
这是 R，这是 B，这是 R，这是 R1，这是 R，这是 R1，R2，等等。
So this is R2, this is R1, this is R2, R3, so this is R2, this is R1,
这是 R2，这是 R1，这是 R2，这是 R3，这是 R2，这是 R1，
this is R2, this is R3, this is R4, so R4 will be the result.
这是 R2，这是 R3，这是 R4，因此结果为 R4。
We finally have 1 to be the output of this gcd value of 999 and then 911.
我们终于得到了 999 和 911 的最大公约数，其值为 1。
So because their gcd value is 1, that means we can find the corresponding x and y.
因为它们的最大公约数为 1，所以我们可以找到相应的 x 和 y 值。
How do we find this x and y? So you see, we go to the
我们如何找到这个 x 和 y？你看，我们去找一下
reverse one. We trace it back. From this one here, one can be represented as R2 minus 5 times R3.
反转一下，我们追溯它的来源。从这一步开始，我们可以将“一个”表示为 R2 减去 5 倍的 R3。
26 minus 5 times 5. So this is R2, this is R3. And R3,
26 减去 5 再乘以 5，这就是 R2，那是 R3。还有 R3，
from the second row, R3 equals 31 minus 1 times 26 from this row.
从第二行起，R3 等于 31 减 1 再乘以 26，从这一行开始。
So we can substitute 5 from the second row. So then, one can be represented as, this is R2,
因此我们可以将第二行的 5 替换掉。那么，1 可以表示为，这就是 R2，
some value of R2 with R1. Because R3 can be represented as, this is R1, this is R2.
因为 R3 可以表示为 R1 和 R2，所以 R2 的某个值与 R1 相关。
R3 can be represented as some combination of R1, R2.
R3 可以表示为 R1 和 R2 的某种组合，表达更为自然。
So 1 equals some beta times R1 times R2. And R2, we can finally, we can, according to
因此 1 等于某些 beta 乘以 R1 和 R2 的乘积。而 R2，我们最终可以，根据
this row, R2 can be represented as R minus R1. So this 26 can be represented as R
这一行，R2 可以表示为 R 减去 R1。因此，这个 26 可以用 R 来表示，表达更为自然。
minus 2 times R1. So finally, one can be represented as R times R something
减去 R1 的两倍，最终可以表示为 R 乘以 R 的某个量
plus or minus something times R1. So 31 can be represented as, so one equals,
加或减某个数乘以 R1，因此 31 可以表示为，也就是说一个等于，这样的表述更为自然易懂。
this R1 can be represented as, number one is B, and it is R. So finally, one can be represented as
这个 R1 可以表示为，数字一对应 B，它是 R。因此，一最终可以表示为
B plus R, some combination. And R can be represented as A, B, some combination.
B 加 R，表示为 A、B 或其他某种组合。
So R comes from here. So R, this 1 equals this B, some number times this A, this B.
因此 R 来源于这里。所以，这个 1 等于这个 B，某个数乘以这个 A，这个 B。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
And finally, one can be represented as this A, this is X, this is B, this is 1.
最后，一个可以表示为这样的 A，这是 X，这是 B，这是 1。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
So finally, we have 1, we are putting the betas, and then A times X because B times 1 equals 1.
最后终于有了 1，我们正在放置测试版，然后是 A 乘以 X，因为 B 乘以 1 等于 1。这句话更自然、更易于理解。
So in this example, because GCD value, so A is 999 times 176.
在这个例子中，由于最大公约数，因此 A 等于 999 乘以 176。
So this is A, this is X, plus B, 911 times minus 193. This equals GCD, A and B, is 1.
这就是 A，这是 X，加上 B，911 次方减去 193。这等于 A 和 B 的最大公约数，为 1。
So this is, X is here, A is here, B is here, Y is here, then here, and this we will trace back.
这就是，X 在这里，A 在这里，B 在这里，Y 在这里，然后在这里，我们将会追溯回去。
This tracing back procedure is called the extended Euclidean algorithm.
这种回溯过程称作扩展欧几里得算法，翻译得更加自然易懂。
So of course, X represents X equals A to the minus 1, the module inverse of A mod B.
当然，X 代表 X 等于 A 的-1 次方，即 A 模 B 的逆元。当然，X 代表 X 等于 A 的-1 次方，即 A 模 B 的逆元。
So X is,
因此 X 是，
sorry, A is 911, right? So here is, change it, A is here, X is here,
对不起，A 是 911，对吧？所以这里要改一下，A 在这里，X 在这里，
B is here, Y is here. So X is equals mass 193 mod 999.
B 和 Y 都在这里，因此 X 的值是 193 除以 999 的余数。
So we take the positive value, the positive should be,
因此我们取正值，正数应该是，这样的表达更为自然易懂
R, X should be 806.
R, X 的值应该是 806。
So in this example, the module inverse of 911, it is 806.
在这个例子中，911 的逆元是 806。
Because 806 times 911 mod 999, it is 1.
因为 806 乘以 911 除以 999 的余数是 1。
The result of 806 times 911 is coming to 1 mod 999.
806 乘以 911 的结果对 999 取模为 1。
So the basis of this equation implies this equation.
因此，这个等式的基础表明了这一点。
So here, this is here, this part is here, change it.
这里，这就是这里，这部分在这里，需要修改一下。
So A is here, this part is X, E is here, this part is 1.
因此 A 在这里，这部分对应 X，E 在这里，这部分对应 1。
This is A, this is B, this is X, 911 is B, sorry, this is 911 is X, so this is X.
这是 A，这是 B，这是 X，911 对应 B，抱歉，911 对应 X，因此这是 X。
So finally, we make it to be correct on the equation.
终于，我们在等式上做到了正确，表达得更加自然易懂。
So the second page actually shows, because according to the basis equation, this GCD
因此，实际上第二页展示的内容是，根据基础方程，这个最大公约数
A is 911, B is here, can be represented as, this is A, this is X, and this B, this is Y.
A 是 911，B 在此处，可以表示为：这是 A，这是 X，这是 B，这是 Y。
So we have 806 is a module inverse of A mod B, this is the module inverse.
因此，806 是 A 模 B 的模逆元，这即是模逆元的定义。
In this example, what's the B mod 1?
在这个例子中，B 除以 1 的余数是多少？
B mod 1 is what?
B 除以 1 等于什么？
B mod A, B mod 1 is what?
B 对 A 取模，B 对 1 取模是什么意思？
Is what, right?
是什么来着，对吧？
176 is B mod 1, because B mod 1 times B mod A equals what?
176 除以 1 的余数是 B，因为 B 除以 1 的余数乘以 B 除以 A 的余数等于多少？
Okay, previously, we have, in exercise one, we have the GCD 93, 16, equals what, right?
好的，之前在第一题中，我们计算了 93 和 16 的最大公约数，等于什么，对吗？
So this is how we can find the module inverse of 16, modular 93.
这就是这样，我们可以找到 16 在模 93 下的逆元。
So can you use 10 minutes to solve this result?
你能花 10 分钟解决这个问题吗？
Okay, this has a break, 10 minutes. Okay, after break, we continue.
好的，这里有休息时间，10 分钟。好的，休息过后我们再继续。